Guide to the Doris Duke American Indian oral history project audio recordings 1949-1972
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Tom Stash, 1968 July 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 384)
  Personal and family background, settling in Blanding, medicine man,
  horses on Blue Mountain.
  Tom Stash speaks in his native language and the interview is conducted through an interpreter Clyde Bernally.
- Tom Stash, 1968 July 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 385-I)
  Translation of interview with Tom Stash (second reel).
  Horses killed on Blue Mountain, fear caused by white men moving in, Mormons killing Navajo, preparing for a squaw dance to cure his stomach problems.
  1 reel-to-reel audiotape, compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 39 minutes.
- Tom Stash, 1968 July 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 385-II)
  Original interview with Tom Stash (second reel).
  1 reel-to-reel audiotape, compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 33 minutes.
- Tom Stash, 1968 July 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 386-I)
  Third reel of an interview with Tom Stash. Original recording with interpreter.
- Tom Stash, 1968 July 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 386-II)
  Translation of the third reel of interview.
  Diagnosis, treatment and billing by medicine man, preparing for Squaw Dance, help from the mission, conversation with Father Wake from the mission, cures by medicine men, sheep and goats being herded away.
- Tom Stash, Katherine Stash, James Samson, 1968 July 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 387-I)
  Original recording with Tom and Katherine Stash.
  Interviewed and recorded by Gary Shumway. Translation by Benjamin Lee.
- Tom Stash, Katherine Stash, James Samson, 1968 July 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 387-II)
  Translation of recording with Tom and Katherine Stash.
  Sons experiences in the military and Vietnam, effects that the war has had on their children, disapproval of war, son's plans after the military.
- Jim Mike, 1968 June 20; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 388)
  Interviewee responds in native language and uses an interpreter.
  Relations with Navajos, Posey being shot/poisoned.
  Sound: 3/4
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 18 minutes.
- Raymond Nakaij, 1968 July; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 389)
  An address given by Raymond Nakaij at the 25th anniversary of the St Christopher's mission in Bluff, Utah.
- Arthur M. Wyatt, 1968 August 28; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 390)
  Growing up on a farm in Colorado, sheep trade, trading post.
  Interviewed and recorded in Durango Colorado.
- Tommy Sobe (Shoshoni), 1967 June 23; 1967 July 11; 1967 August 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 391)
  Side1:
  Track 1-5 Eardine Harney- 1967 August 11 'Skunk and Woodpecker'
  Track 6- Eardine Harney- 1967 August 11 'Rabbits' End of Track'
  End of Track 6- beginning of Track 7- Eardine Harney- 1967 August 11 'An Owl Story'
  Track 7- Jimmie Blackhat 'Two Divers story 2' continued
  Track 8- Tommy Sobe- 1967 June 23 'White's arrival' in English
  Track 11- Jimmy blackhat and Eardine Harney- conversation on peyote- 1967 August 11
  Side2:
  Track 1- Mrs Margaret Hooper 1967 July 11 '(someone?)..marrying his daughter'
  Track 3-'Zoavich?'
  Track 4-'The Blind Coyote'
  Track 5- 'Coyote and Porcupine'
  Track 7- 'Bear and Deer'
  Middle of Track 8- 'The Number of Deaths' and 'Cotton Tail'
  Track 10- 'Antelope and Badger' and 'The Theft of Fire' 1967 July 14
  Track 11- 'The Theft of Pine Nuts'
  Reel-to-reel audiotape, CD copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 57 minutes.
- Paul D. Irwin, 1968 September 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 392)
- Bruce Shumway, 1968 August 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 393)
- Albert L. Lyman, 1968 July 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 394)
- Albert L. Lyman, 1968 July 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 395)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 2 minutes.
- Albert L. Lyman, 1968 July 31; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 396)
- Albert L. Lyman, 1968 July 31; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 397)
- Albert L. Lyman, 1968 July 31; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 398)
- Albert L. Lyman, 1968 August 03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 399)
- Sadie Benally (Navajo), 1968 July 02; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 400-I)
  400-1_01 Translation of original interview.
  400-I_02 continuation of translated interview
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 26 minutes.
- Sadie Benally (Navajo), 1968 July 02; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 400-II)
  400-II_01 Original interview with Sadie Benally and Clyde Benally as interpreter
  400-II_02 continued
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 401-419)
- Bonnie Atine, 1968 August 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 420)
  Last half of track three is something that was taped over at a high speed.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 15 minutes.
- Harry Dutchie, 1968 July 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 421)
- Madiline Cameron, 1968 June 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 422)
- Madiline Cameron, 1968 June 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 423)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 17 minutes.
- Ida Vijil, 1968 July 22; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 424)
- Jim Vijil, 1968 July 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 425)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total Running time 1 hour 6 minutes.
- Jim Vijil, 1968 July 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 426)
- Bruce Shumway, 1968 August 06; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 427)
- Bruce Shumway, 1968 August 06; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 428)
- Bruce Shumway, 1968 August 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 429)
- Bruce Shumway, 1968 August 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 430)
- Bruce Shumway, 1968 August 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 431)
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 432-452)
- Leo S. Vicenti (Jicarilla Apache), 1968 June 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 453)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour.
  Interviewed and recorded by Karl Young in Dulce, New Mexico.
- Leo S. Vicenti, Harper Vicenti (Jicarilla Apache), 1968 June 19; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 454)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 55 minutes.
- Gustina Smith Hawkins (Non-Native Associated with Utes), 1968 May; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 455)
  Mother's photography shop, recreation.
- Suwim Fielding and Jane Honga, 1968 April 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 456)
  Suwim Fielding tracks 1-9
  Jane Honga end of track 9- end
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 9 minutes.
- Recording unavailable (Reel 457)
- Jane Honga, Lacey Toskie, Loly Toskie, 1968 April; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 458)
  Jane Honga 1-5 Lacey Toskie 6- Loly Toskie half of track 9- end
- Recording unavailable (Reel 459)
- Lena Sixkiller (Northern Ute) LaRena Iorg, 1968 July 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 460)
- LaRena Iorg, 1968 July 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 461)
- Nellie Mahone, L. Ferra, 1968 May 31; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 462)
- Recording unavailable (Reel 463)
- Suwim Fielding, Frank Beecher, Mamie Engel, 1968 July 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 464)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 34 minutes.
- Augustine Mirabel (Taos), 1968 June 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 465)
  Personal history, employment, welfare, farming, alcohol.
  Interviewed and recorded by Karl Young in Taos Pueblo, New Mexico.
- Augustine Mirabel (Taos), 1968 June 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 466)
  Hunting, a story of a practical joke, travel, farming, shelters.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 28 5 minutes.
- Mrs. Augustine Mirabel (Taos), 1968 June 28; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 467)
  Personal history, Nurse training, education, alcohol, occupations, welfare, food, living conditions, religion, farming, employment, health, community relations.
- Joe Trinidad Archuleta (Taos), 1969 June 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 468)
  Joe Trinidad discusses spending the summer with his sister to raise crops on land shares. After harvest he returns to his home in Taos New Mexico.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 47 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Karl Young in San Juan, New Mexico.
- Raymond Fragua (Jemez Pueblo), 1968 July; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 469)
  Interviewed and recorded by Karl Young in New Mexico.
- Felipe Fragua Whitecloud (Jemez Pueblo), 1968 June 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 470)
  Interviewed and recorded by Karl Young in Albequerqui, New Mexico.
- Antonio Fragua Whitecloud (Jemez Pueblo), 1968 August; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 471)
  Life outside of Jemez with his wife.
  Interviewed and recorded by Karl Young.
- Sheldon Luna (Navajo), 1968 July 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 472)
  Education, employment mining.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 20 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Gary Shumway and Clyde Benally in Blanding, Utah.
- Irene Shorty, 1968 August 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 473)
  Interviewer not identified at beginning of tape.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 9 minutes.
- Jackson Gray Mountain (Navajo), 1968 June 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 474-I)
  Recorded in native language with intepreter.
  Interviewed and recorded by Gary Shumway, translation by Benjamin Lee.
- Jackson Gray Mountain (Navajo), 1968 June 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 474-II)
  (Tape 2 is the translation of Tape 1)
  Reel-to-reel audiotape, CD copy, compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 3 minutes.
- Ben Whitehorse, 1968 July 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 475-I)
  Original interview
- Ben Whitehorse, 1968 July 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 475-II)
  Translation of original interview.
- Rosita Issac, 1968 June 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 476)
- Evan Smith, 1968 June 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 477)
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 49 minutes.
- Ruth Claw, 1968 July 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 478-I)
  Original interview in native language.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 30 minutes.
- Ruth Claw, 1968 July 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 478-II)
  Translation of previous tape.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 2 hours 2 minutes.
- Ralph W. Evans, 1968 June 13; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 479)
- Recording unavailable (Reel 480)
- John Dayish, 1968 June 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 481-I)
  Translation of Interview
  interviewed and recorded by Gary Shumway, Translation by Benjamin Lee.
- John Dayish, 1968 June 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 481-II)
  Original Interview
- John Dayish, 1968 June 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 481-III)
- John Dayish, 1968 June 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 481-IV)
- Recording unavailable (Reel 482)
- Lewis Gray (Navajo Adopted by Utes), 1968 August 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 483-I)
  Original interview recorded in native language.
  interviewed and recorded by Gary Shumway, translation by Benjamin Lee.
- Lewis Gray (Navajo Adopted by Utes), 1968 August 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 483-II)
- Anna Marie Ketchum Nat (Ute), 1968 June 20; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 484)
  Education, Paiute-Ute relations, Ute-Navajo relations, intermarriage, Ute-Navajo riot, employment, National awareness, Voting, Vietnam, alcohol, hippies.
  Interviewed and recorded by Gary Shumway and Clyde Benally in White Mesa, Utah.
- Norman Begay (Navajo), 1968 August; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 485)
- John Katso, Iris Atini Katso, 1968 June 22; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 486-I)
  Original recording in Native language.
- John Katso, Iris Atini Katso, 1968 June 22; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 486-II)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 45 minutes.
- John Katso, Iris Atini Katso, 1968 June 22; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 486-III)
- John Katso, Iris Atini Katso, 1968 June 22; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 486-IV)
- Recording unavailable (Reel 487)
- Father Wayne Valdez, Raymond Nakai, 1966 July 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 488)
  Father Wayne Pontius and Chairman Raymond Nakai where interviewed by Dave Murdock and Gary Shumway for a radio broadcast.
- Wilbert Willy, Tina Willy, 1968 June 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 489)
- Mary Goodman Gillis, 1968 August 03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 490)
- Charles Keith, 1967 June 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 491-I)
  Original recording with some portions in Navajo.
  Family history, owning sheep, trading posts, etc.
  Interviewed and recorded by Gary Shumway in Blanding Utah; Interperated by Clyde Benally.
- Charles Keith, 1967 June 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 491-II)
  Translation of Navajo portions of the tape.
- Recording unavailable (Reel 492)
  Because of the poor condition of the audio recording this interviews is available only in transcript form. Please see the Doris Duke oral history project in the Manuscripts Division of Special Collections (Ms 417).
- Angelina Frances Medina, 1968 June 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 493)
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 45 minutes.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 494-496)
- Eugene Tapahantso, 1968 August 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 497)
  Reel-to-reel audiotape, CD copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 28 minutes.
- Tom Lee, 1968 August 05; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 498)
- Lynn Lee, 1968 July 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 499)
- Lynn Lee, 1968 July 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 500)
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 35 minutes.
- Lynn Lee, 1968 July 31; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 501)
- Lynn Lee, 1968 July 31; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 502)
- Lynn Lee, 1968 July 31; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 503)
- Mildred Tso, 1968 June 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 504)
- Mildred Tso, 1968 June 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 505)
- Jane Goodman, 1968 July 26; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 506)
- Jane Goodman, 1968 July 26; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 507)
- Henry Samson, Jene Samson, Roy Samson, 1968 July 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 508-I)
- Henry Samson, Jene Samson, Roy Samson, 1968 July 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 508-II)
  Original interview.
- James Samson, 1968 July 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 509)
  James Samson is the grandson of the Stashes
  Tape two of interview 2 with Tom Stash and his wife Katherine Stash at Bluff, Utah
- Roy Samson, 1968 August 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 510)
  2 reel-to-reel audiotapes
- Fernandez Begay, Nancy Yanito, John Shorty, 1968 August 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 511)
  Interviewee not identified at beginning of tape- recorded in native language.
- Nancy Yanito, John Shorty, 1968 August 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 512)
  Group discussion.
- Brother Juniper, 1968 August 03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 513)
- Brother Juniper, 1968 August 03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 514)
- Roy Atine, 1968 August 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 515)
- Recording unavailable (Reel 516)
- Harry Dutchie, 1968 July 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 517)
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 518-524)
- Earl Livermore (Blackfoot), Earl Baker, Buster McCurdy (Goshute), 1970 April 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 525)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 2 hours 10 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by John D. Sylvester.
- Oshley Navajo (Navajo), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 526-I)
  Interviewee not identified at beginning of tape
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 54 minutes.
  Translation by Benjamin Lee.
- Oshley Navajo (Navajo), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 526-II)
  Translated from original tape.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 28 minutes.
- Indian Dances, 1967; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 527)
  Piaute songs, Native American Dances
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 14 minutes.
- Episcopal Mass, 1968 July 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 528)
  Episcopal Mass celebration at St. Christopher's Mission in Bluff, Utah for the twenty-fifth anniversary of the founding of the Mission.
- Jane White, 1968 July 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 529)
- Gladys Perkins Lyman, 1968 August 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 530)
- Recording unavailable (Reel 531)
- Helena Pacheco (Half Sioux, Half Winnebago), 1970 June 22; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 532)
  Recorded at the Fort Lewis College in Durango, Colorado.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 533-544)
- Larry Dennison (Navajo), 1970 July 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 545)
  Recorded in Salt Lake City, Utah.
- Clarice Chapoose (Half Ute, Half Shoshoni), 1970 July; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 546)
- Shirley Reed (Ute), 1970 July; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 547)
- Shirley Reed (Ute), 1970 July; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 548)
  Native American Legends.
- Larry Dennison (Navajo), 1970 July 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 549)
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 550-562)
- Lauraine McKenzie (Navajo), 1970 June 22; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 563)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 40 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by at the Fort Lewis College in Durango, Colorado.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 564-599)
- Mr. and Mrs. Ferra; Maude Sinyella; Suwim Fielding, 1968 June 7; 1968 July 08; 1968 July 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 600)
- Gertrude Chapoose Willie (Ute), 1970 July 23; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 601)
- Lula Brock Wash, Gertrude Chapoose Willie (Ute), 1970 July 23; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 602)
- Joseph Pinnecoose, 1970; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 603)
  Interviewed and recorded by Norma Denver
- Joseph Pinnecoose, 1970 July 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 604)
- Mariette Reed (Ute), 1970; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 605)
  Ute Legends told to Mariette by her Grandmother.
- Katherine Jenkins, 1970 July 23; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 606)
- Lorenzo Chavez (Zuni), 1970 July 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 607)
  Interviewed and recorded by: Gregory C. Crampton, John D. Sylvester, Gordon Peywa, and Virginia Anderson.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 608-616)
- Ross Harden, 1970 July 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 617)
  Interviewed and recorded by Gregory C. Crampton and F. A. O'Neil.
- Ross Harden, 1970 July 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 618)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 12 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Gregory. C Thompson, F. A. O'Neil, and John D. Sylvester.
- Ross Harden, 1970 July 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 619)
  Interviewed and recorded by Gregory C. Thompson, F. A. O'Neil, and John D. Sylvester.
- Ross Harden, 1970 July 21; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 620)
  Interviewed and recorded by F. A. O'Neil.
- Ross Harden, 1970 August 13; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 621)
  Interviewed and recorded by F. A. O'Neil and Gregory C. Thompson.
- Peter MacDonald (Navajo), 1970 August 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 622)
- Peter MacDonald (Navajo), 1970 August 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 623)
- Melvin Thom (Paiute), 1970 August 06; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 624)
  A conference or class presentation.
  Interviewed and recorded by F. A. O'Neil
- Melvin Thom (Paiute), 1970 August 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 625)
  Sit down interview following presentation on previous tape.
- Syme Sanchez (Acoma Pueblo), 1970 August 23; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 626)
  This interview was recorded while walking about the Mission Church and Convent at Sky City, Acoma. Topics discussed include the Acoma Pueblo Church and it's: Choir Loft, Nave, Baptistry, Cemetery, Altar, St. Stephen's Statue, Oil Paintings, Qirshmer Report, Pumpkin Designs, Sanctuary, Convent, Tools, Stairwell, and Storeroom.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 2 hours 23 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Dr. Ward Alan Minge in Acoma Pueblo (Sky City), New Mexico.
- Syme Sanchez (Acoma Pueblo), 1970 September 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 627)
  Acoma Pueblo Church, Pueblo Revolt, The coming of The Spanish.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 31 minutes.
- Glenna Jenks (Ute), 1970 August; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 628)
  "Indian Princess", "Miss Indian Utah", talking about Indian students in school.
- Glenna Jenks (Ute), 1970 August; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 629)
  Continuation of tape 628, Feelings of Indian children, inferiority, schooling.
- Lucille Thompson, 1970 September 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 630)
  Interviewed and recorded by F. A. O'Neil and Gregory C. Thompson in Durango Colorado.
- Lucille Thompson, 1970 September 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 631)
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd O'Neil and Gregory Thompson.
- Dr. Robert Delaney, 1970 September 01; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 632)
  Interviewed and recorded by Gregory Thompson and F. A. O'Neil in Durango, Colorado.
- Buford Wayt, 1970 September 03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 633)
- Erwin Bowman, 1970 September 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 634)
  Interviewed and recorded by Gregory Thompson and F. A. O'Neil in Shiprock New Mexico.
- Recording unavailable (Reel 635)
- Mr. and Mrs. Ira Hatch, 1970 September 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 636)
- Randall Taylor, 1970 September 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 637)
- Gary Pinnicoose, 1970 September 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 638)
- Donald Kee, 1970 September 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 639)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 29 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Gregory Thompson and F. A. O'Neil in Shiprock, New Mexico.
- Morrill Turner (Non-Native Associated with Southern Ute), 1968 September 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 640)
  Emmett Wirt, Caucasian-Native American relations, trade, land, cattle business, employment, education.
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil, Gregory Thompson, and John D. Sylvester in Durango, Colorado.
- Morrill Turner, 1968 September 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 641)
- Recording unavailable (Reel 642)
- Keith Grass, 1971 September 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 643)
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil in Shiprock, New Mexico.
- Joe Kieyoomia, 1970 September 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 644)
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil, Gregory C. Thompson, and John D. Sylvester in Shiprock, New Mexico.
- Shirley Murdock Reed (Northern Ute), 1968 August 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 645)
  Termination, education.
- Tully Linclon, 1970 September 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 646-I)
  Original recording in native language.
  Interviewed and recorded by John D. Sylvester and David M. Brugge.
- Tully Linclon, 1970 September 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 646-II)
  Continuation of translation on tape 646-III_01,02.
- Tully Linclon, 1970 September 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 646-III)
  Translation on tape 646-I_01,02. Continues on 646-II.
- Recording unavailable (Reel 647)
- Jack Todichiini, Mrs. Pete or Besh Bitoh Asdzaan (Navajo), 1960 November 28; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 648-649)
  Land Claims, background, and Headmen.
  2 reel-to-reel audiotape, compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 4 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by J. L. Correll in Window Rock, Arizona.
- Besh Bitoh Beh Asdzaan "Mrs. Pete", Mary Bahe, Lew Wallace, Hosteen Nez Blackgoat (Navajo), 1960 November 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 650-651)
  2 reel-to-reel audiotapes, compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 2 minutes.
- Hosteen Nez Blackgoat (Navajo), 1960 November 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 652)
  Land Claims, Background, and Headmen.
- Hosten Nez Blackgoat and Bitsi Chilly Begay, Pete Totsooni, 1960 December 01; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 653)
  Land Claims, Background, Headmen, Raids, Shelters, Hogans.
  Interviewee not identified at beginning of tape.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 2 hours 7 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by D. M. Brugge